<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anders Ellern Bilgrau</title><link>https://bilgrau.com/en/</link><description>Recent content on Anders Ellern Bilgrau</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>da-dk</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bilgrau.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hierarchical Edge Bundles in R</title><link>https://bilgrau.com/en/posts/hierachical-edge-bundles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bilgrau.com/en/posts/hierachical-edge-bundles/</guid><description>Hierarchical edge bundling of a gene network. Blue indicate negative correlations, red indicate positive. The darker the color, the more strong the correlation.
Background During the finalization of my PhD, I implemented the so-called Hierarchical Edge Bundling plotting method for a paper now published in the Annals of Applied Statistics. Though the plot above sadly did not make the final cut, I admit due to an lack of added value, it appeared in the original submission and the thesis.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio</title><link>https://bilgrau.com/en/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bilgrau.com/en/portfolio/</guid><description>Cases Section of Orthodontics, University of Aarhus Statistical analysis of material from Peter Bangsgaard Stoustrup, Section of Orthodontics, University of Aarhus. We estimated the incidence of orofacial complications as well as identified predictors of dentofacial growth abnormalities in patients with Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (JIA) also known as rheumatoid arthritis.
Hematology Department, Aalborg University Co-developer of hemaClass.org , a web application that classifies genetic samples of patients with diffuse large-cell B-cell lymphoma and myeloma into prognostic groups for survival.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://bilgrau.com/en/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bilgrau.com/en/about/</guid><description>Backgrund I am a statistician with a flair for programming and a self-driven creative urge. I am a Ph.D. in (bio)statistics and a master in applied mathematics specializing in statistics. Both degrees were obtained through an interdisciplinary collaboration with the Department of Mathematical Sciences, Aalborg University, and the Hematological Department, Aalborg University Hospital.
Visualisering af et gen-netværk
In short, my PhD project consisted of a number of methods in high-dimensional statistics on reproducibility and data integration with applications in molecular cancer biology.</description></item></channel></rss>